准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
怪东西
分镜总监
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
技术总监
动画总监
制片指导
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
太安静了
It's too quiet
这附近有点不对劲
Something isn't right around here
该不会是
Could it be?
海绵宝宝今天傍晚不在
SpongeBob is gone for the evening
敬与你共处的美妙傍晚  公共台
Here's to a delightful evening
alone with you, public television
再来再来
Do it again, do it again
好
OK
你们两个能不能别吵了
Will you two be quiet?
我还要看公共台呢
I'm trying to watch public television
再来再来
Do it again, do it again
要是他俩傍晚想害我在家都不得安宁
If those two want to ruin my quiet evening at home
那可差得远了
they're gonna have to do better than that
干嘛
What?
章鱼哥
Squidward
你们该不会还在吧
You're still there, aren't you?
傍晚好  章鱼哥
Good evening, Squidward
别急
Not so fast
你们两个小畜生休想害我傍晚不好过
You two little monsters aren't about to ruin my evening
我们才没要害你不好过
We're not here to ruin it
我们是要让你更好过
We're here to enhance it
对不对啊  派大星
Isn't that right, pat?
对  我们是来
Yeah, we're here
我章鱼哥都这么努力了
Can't a hard-working squid
就不能自个看会儿电视吗
get a little TV time alone?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
派大星
Patrick?
又有什么意义
What's the point
能不能放大声点
Could you turn it up?
章鱼哥
Squidward?
能不能关小声点
Could you turn it down a little?
章鱼哥  这是演什么的
Squidward, what's this about?
章鱼哥  他怎么这么有感染力
Squidward, how come he's so emotional?
他是不是反派
Is he the bad guy?
章鱼哥
Squidward?
够了
That's it
我只想看公共台放的轻柔爵士
All I wanted to do
was watch some smooth jazz on public television
然而很明显  根本就看不了
But apparently, that's not gonna happen
我又得离开我自己的家
Once again, I'm going to have to leave my own home
图个安宁了
just to get some peace and quiet
好好看我家电视去
Enjoy my TV
等下  这我好像看过
Wait, I think I've seen this before
这段可搞笑了
This part's funny
我打算去个遥远的地方
I'm gonna go somewhere far away
远离那两个家伙
Somewhere far away from those two
用我电视看公共台的那两个家伙
Watching public television on my TV
他们不可能懂真正的文化
They wouldn't know real culture
就算它像载满水泥的卡车撞过来也一样
even if it hit them like a truck full of cement
应该是第五天吧
Day five, I think
我在田野之上摇摆而行
I've been waddling these fields
又饿又累  还迷了路
I'm hungry, tired, and lost
唯一的优点就是  没有海绵宝宝
The only good thing about this is, no SpongeBob
水母田
Jellyfish fields
那是什么怪东西  派大星
What is that thing, Patrick?
不知道
I don't know
过去看一下
Let's get a closer look
嗨  陌生人
Hi, stranger
我是海绵宝宝
I am SpongeBob
等一下
Wait a minute
他可能不是怪物
Maybe he's not a monster
应该是只濒危物种
Maybe he's an endangered species
应该要救助他
We should help him
对  救助他
Yeah, help him
滚开
Go away
看不出来没人要你吗
Can't you tell nobody wants you?
你都濒危了
You're endangered
那样不对的
Not like that
胸怀爱心就能照顾好他
With lots of love and affection, we can take care of him
小臭臭  到了
Well, smelly, here you are
你的新家
Your new home
小臭臭  一定会特别棒
Oh, smelly, this is gonna be great
我们马上就是快乐大家庭了
We'll be one big happy family
我带你参观一下
Let me show you around
这是你的床  小臭臭
Here's your bed, smelly
小臭臭
这是你的食盆
Here's your food bowl
还有宠物粮
And some kibble
蜗牛粮
你可以住这儿一辈子了
You can live here forever and ever
派大星你看
Look, pat
他喜极而泣了
He's crying tears of joy
小臭臭  你还有一位家庭成员没见
Well, smelly, there's one more
family member you haven't met
小臭臭  这位是小蜗
Smelly, meet Gary
快看啊  小臭臭
Look at that, smelly
小蜗喜欢你
Gary likes you
小蜗  不行
Gary, no
小蜗
Gary
小蜗好像不喜欢小臭臭
I don't think Gary likes smelly
对啊  小蜗从来没那样攻击过别人
Yeah, Gary's never attacked anyone like that
除了章鱼哥
except Squidward
看来小臭臭不能住这了
I guess smelly can't live here
他可以来跟我住
He can come live with me
真是个好办法  派大星
That's a great idea, Patrick
你一直都很想养宠物
You've always wanted a pet
是不是很可爱
Isn't that cute?
看看他要住你家有多兴奋啊
Look how excited he is to get to your house
再见  小臭臭
Bye, smelly
祝你派大星家住得开心
Have fun at Patrick's
不行  小臭臭
No, no, smelly
章鱼哥可不喜欢宠物
Squidward doesn't like pets
小臭臭  要玩捡球吗
Hey, smelly, wanna play catch?
放心  你很快就学得会了
Don't worry, you'll get the hang of it
差一点
Almost
再来
Again
就差一点了
So close
好  这下你
Yeah, now you're
小臭臭
Smelly
你什么毛病
What's gotten into you?
喂  动物管理局
Hello, animal control
我家闯进了只野生动物
There's a wild animal loose in my house
好  我不挂电话
Sure, I'll hold
小臭臭  回来
Smelly, come back
小臭臭
Smelly
不许动
Freeze
这是在闹什么闹
What's all the commotion
你们被包围了
You are surrounded
动物园
已经无路可逃了
There is no way out
小臭臭
Smelly
不好意思
Excuse me
借过一下
Pardon me
挪过去就行了
If I can just scooch through there
不好意思
Excuse me
借过一下
Pardon me
不好意思
Excuse me
你们别来烦小臭臭
You leave smelly alone
他就只是只可怜又呆傻的野生动物
He's just a poor, dumb, wild animal
野生动物不属于这里  小子
Wild animals don't belong here, son
只属于动物园
They belong in the zoo
抓起来
Get him, boys
动物园
小臭臭
Smelly
不明物种
妈妈  那是什么怪东西
Mommy, what is that thing?
不知道  不过它丑死了
I don't know, but it's hideous, isn't it?
这可不好
This isn't good
你说得可对了
You're absolutely right
它得加芥末酱
It needs mustard
谁都不应该被那样对待
No one should be treated like that
更何况是跟小臭臭一样丑的家伙
Not even someone as ugly as smelly
这种事一定要让我们出手
Something needs to be done about this
而我正好知道怎么出手
and I know exactly what that thing is
好的  派大星
OK, Patrick
还记得计划吗
Remember the plan?
记得
Yeah
是这个吗
This one, right?
不是那个
No, not that
我说的是让小臭臭越狱的计划
I'm talking about the plan
to break smelly out of this animal prison
好计划
Good plan
好  我先下
All right, I'll go down first
注意警戒  跟紧我
Keep a lookout and follow me
你是我的英雄
You're my hero
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
救命
Help
会被抓的
We'll get caught
什么  我听不见
What, I can't hear you
我喊得太大声了
I'm screaming too loud
不用再怕了  亲爱的小臭臭
Fear no longer, dear smelly
我们来救你了
We are here to rescue you
明白吗
Understand?
我们来接你回家
We are taking you home
看他有多兴奋啊
Look how excited he is
开关打开  派大星
Flip the switch, Patrick
小臭臭  你自由了
Smelly, you're free
你们被包围了
You're surrounded
逃也没用
There's no use trying to run
派大星  快逃啊
Run, Patrick, run
快一点  派大星
Faster, Patrick
我会让小臭臭先跑
I'll let smelly go first
别怕  小臭臭
Don't worry, smelly
你有我们肯定安全
You're safe with us
应该甩掉了
Think we lost 'em
我们又是快乐大家庭了
Well, we're all one big happy family again
来看看这黑漆漆的下水道通向哪里
Let's see where this dark sewer tunnel leads
没事的  小臭臭
It's all right, smelly
我们马上就能回到家
Soon we'll be home
你马上就能睡在
and you can sleep in that
你心爱又舒服的宠物提篮里了
cozy little pet carrier you love so much
我看到光了
I see light
还真是  派大星
You're right, Patrick
那一定就是出口
that must be the way out
那是什么地方
Where are we?
去问他们吧
Let's go ask those guys
不好意思
Excuse us?
他们跟你长得好像
They look just like you
去吧  陪你真正的家人吧
Go, be with your real family
快去吧  小臭臭
Go ahead, smelly
我知道你把我们当家人
I know you've come to think of us as a family
但是这样才更好
but it's better this way
我会想念他的  海绵宝宝
I'm gonna miss him, SpongeBob
我也是  兄弟
Me too, buddy
我也是
Me too
但他现在陪着同类  他属于那个地方
But he's with his own kind now, where he belongs
既然如此  回到属于我们的地方吧
And on that note, let us go back to where we belong
你们好  我的孩子们
Salutations, my children
准备好聆听每日一曲轻柔爵士了没
Are you ready for your daily dose of smooth jazz?
嗨
Hi
天灵灵
地灵灵
分镜总监
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
技术总监
动画总监
制片指导
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
加油  炉子
Come on, "stovey"
快爆啊
pop that corn
准备好  小蜗
Get ready, Gary
要来了
Incoming
爆米花好了
Popcorn is served
那位老兄是洗车场的克星
That bro is trouble at any car wash
广告过后继续收看  裤头村洗车场
We will return to Bikini Bottom car wash
after these messages
你是个无聊的人吗
Are you boring?
对  我无聊
Yes, yes I am
你朋友会用枯燥乏味这四字形容你吗
When friends describe you
do they use words like "dull," or "drab?"
枯燥
乏味
还有平凡这俩字
Don't forget "platitudinous"
平凡
还真是  查理
Yes, that too, Charlie
但要是我对你说  你能改变那一切呢
But what if I told you that you could change all that
只要有神奇的
with the magic of
魔法
magic
我样子好像个魔法师
I look like some kind of magician
这下我不会被无视了
Now people won't ignore me
但愿是这样  查理
Let's hope not, Charlie
大法师神奇魔法装备在手
With my Mr. Magic magical magic kit
就连你都能惊艳你朋友
even you can impress and amaze your friends
我想惊艳我朋友
I want to impress and amaze my friends
把十九块九毛五汇给我大法师
Just send $1995 to me, Mr. Magic
裤头村邮局
寄件
四到六周后
一套魔法装备  还有个黄色玩意
One magic kit, and another one of these yellow things
到货了
Here it is
大法师神奇魔法装备
Mr. Magic's magical magic kit
看看这么多好货
Look at all this
咒语书
一本咒语书  我专属的奇想魔杖
A book of spells, my very own wand of whimsy
妖僧拉斯普京之须
The beard of Rasputin
当然还有  至关重要的修炼法术执照
And of course, the all-important license
to practice magic
章鱼哥
Squidward
他一定会欣赏我新学到的法力
He'll appreciate my newly-delivered skill
盐汽水  低脂海草片
Brine soda, low-fat seaweed crisps
冷爵士
cool jazz
章鱼哥  又办到了
Squidward, you have done it
你都把自己给惯坏了
You have officially spoiled yourself rotten
那你就继续惯坏自己吧  朋友
Well, let the rotting continue, friend
我要惊艳你  使出
while I impress and amaze you with
魔法
magic
魔法吗
Magic?
你能让自己消失吗  海绵宝宝
Can you make yourself disappear, SpongeBob?
章鱼哥笨死了
Silly Squidward
得升上十级法师才能学消失咒
I won't learn vanishing spells
until I become a level 10 wizard
最好先从简单点的法术施起
No, I'd better start with something simpler
来召唤卡牌
Say, card conjuring
给  拿着这张单纯的卡牌
Here, hold this simple playing card
咒语书
我要在你眼前把它变成魔法卡牌
while I transform it into a magic playing card
before your very eyes
来看看
Let's see
第一步
Step one
一时半会儿多半做不完
This can't possibly end soon
紧接着就是
Which brings us to
第三步
Step three
杂耍东西
Juggle something
耍就耍吧  大法师
Well, if you insist, Mr. Magic
公交站
不管你去哪  总之带我走就对了
I don't care where you're going
just take me away from here
然后  拿出一张牌塞你耳朵里
Then, take one card and shove it in your ear
可我不喜欢开心果
But I don't like pistachio
那你干嘛要开心果味的
Then why did you ask for it?
最后念咒语  天灵灵海灵灵
And finally, just say the words "hobris-pobris"
章鱼哥
Squidward
我简单的卡牌魔法把你变成冰淇淋了
My simple card trick
has turned you into an ice cream cone
所以说
Which means
我就是十级法师
I am a level 10 wizard
看来该把你变回章鱼形态了
I suppose I should change you back to squid form
我变
Presto
来看看
Let's see
阿拉卡扎
A-la-kazam
阿布拉卡达布拉
Abracadabra
乌格里度格里
Oogly-doogly
活不拉括不拉
Hobra-cobra
芝麻开门
Open sesame?
求你变回章鱼哥咒
Change-oh back-oh to Squidward-oh, please-oh
真对不起  章鱼哥
I am so sorry, Squidward
我害你变成了美味的乳味冰淇淋
I've transformed you into a delicious dairy dessert
结果变不回来了
and I can't change you back
没事的  章鱼哥
There, there, Squidward
没必要哭的
There is no need to cry
我发誓  你一定会恢复原状
I promise you will continue your normal life
虽然你现在可以吃
despite the fact that you are now edible
礁石影院
冰
章鱼哥  跟我说话啊
Squidward, speak to me
说话啊
Speak
章鱼哥
Hey, squid
没事吧
Are you OK?
章鱼哥
Hey, squid
你现在还没事吧
Are you still OK?
章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
我有东西要给你
I got something for you
是个伴  陪你一起坐在乏味的冰箱里
Someone to keep you company in that drab old freezer
他们真可爱啊
Aren't they cute?
我发誓要永远守护我的好朋友
I promise to stand by as an eternal guard over my buddy
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
你在干什么
What you doing?
我把可怜的章鱼哥变成了冰淇淋
I have turned poor Squidward into a frozen dessert
太糟了
That's awful
真惨啊
How tragic
章鱼哥真可怜
Poor Squidward
都是我的错
It's all my fault
你刚说了冰淇淋吗
Did you say frozen dessert?
对  我把他变成了华夫蛋筒软冰淇淋
Yeah, I turned him into a tasty soft serve
with a waffle cone
软冰淇淋啊
Soft serve
派大星
Patrick
别吃章鱼哥了
Stop eating Squidward
抱歉
Sorry
派大星
Patrick
可他真太好吃了
But he's so tasty
派大星  你就没听懂吗
Look, Patrick, don't you understand?
这根本就不是你平时吃的冰淇淋
This isn't just your ordinary ice cream cone
是开心果味的
It's pistachio
不对  那是章鱼哥
No, it's Squidward
不管出了什么事
And no matter what happens
我都答应过要看护他
I promised him that I would watch over him
就算他变软冰淇淋  也要让他好好活
to ensure his soft frozen life is unchanged
派大星
Patrick
章鱼哥融化了
Squidward has melted
快报警啊
Quick, call the police
我该怎么办
What am I gonna do?
海神王啊  全都要怪我
Oh, Neptune, it's all my fault
我干了什么
What have I done?
全都要怪你
It's all your fault
我诅咒你  大法师神奇魔法装备
Curse you, Mr. Magic magical magic kit
我诅咒你
Curse you
有了
That's it
问题的答案出现了
There's the answer to our problems
警告
"Warning
仅限9至99岁玩耍
From ages nine to 99"
不对  派大星
No, Patrick
大法师企业
海洋裤头村
魔法师1942号
是那个能帮上忙的大神
The one mystic being that can help us
大法师
Mr. Magic
顺着棕色的砖瓦路走
Just follow the brown tile road
去寻找最神秘的大师
to the most mysterious mystic of 'em all
从来没有谁亲眼见过他
No one's ever seen him in person
请进
Enter
谁这么大胆  敢来见大法师
Who dares to see Mr. Magic?
报上名来
Speak up
是我  海绵那个宝宝
It is I, SpongeBob of the SquarePants
一级魔法师
magician level one
我把我朋友变成冰淇淋了
And I have changed my friend into ice cream
表现得不错
Good job
多谢了  可是
Well, thank you, but
我没法把他给变回去啊
Well, I can't change him back
有没有考虑过换个爱好
Well, have you ever thought of a different hobby?
我需要你帮忙把他变回来
I need your help to change him back
我帮忙吗
My help?
还是免了吧
No thank you
你不帮忙  我朋友永远都变不回来了
But if you don't, my friend will be a cone forever
抱歉  我
Sorry, I, um
我  去吃午饭了
I'm, out to lunch
就这样
that's it
我可以等
I'll wait
我这午饭得吃两年
I'm on a two-year lunch
拜托
Oh, please
别吵
Silence
可是法师  别人都没有你这般的法力
But sir, no one else has your power of sorcery
谢谢
Thank you
海绵宝宝  那边有个谁对着管子讲话
Hey, SpongeBob, there's a guy over here
talking into a tubey thing
别理你朋友
Ignore your friend
你看到的鱼只是个幻象
The fish you see is only an illusion
他怎么在跟大法师说一样的话
Why's he saying the same thing Mr. Magic's saying?
不知道  派大星
I don't know, Patrick
你是谁  先生
Who are you, good sir?
那个
Well, uh
我是霍瑞斯达法师
I'm Horace B. Magic
你就是大法师吗
Are you Mr. Magic?
真名确实就那个
Technically, yes
但这里真正的魔法就是生意的魔法
But the only magic around here is the magic of business
所以说你没法把我朋友变回来了吗
Does that mean you can't change my friend back?
恐怕没法了
I'm afraid not
真遗憾  小子
So sorry about that, laddie
退款支票已经邮寄给你了
Your refund check is in the mail
我不需要退款
I don't need a refund
我只想救回我朋友
I want my friend back
根本就不是钱的问题
This isn't about money
你就只是个假货
You're nothing but a fake
骗人的集团商人
Just a lying, corporate businessman
你纸醉金迷  玷污了魔法
tainting the purity of magic
with your corrupt, commercial ways
你害我对魔法失去了信任
You have ruined my faith in the magical arts
保安
Security
出口
章鱼哥要怎么办
What are we gonna do about Squidward?
随时都能吃了他
We could always eat him
我都有点饿了
I'm kind of hungry
大法师是假的
Mr. Magic was a fake
他的魔法玩意也都是假的
And all of his magic stuff is fake
那些咒语也都是假的
All those magic words, they were fake
压基沙基扒皮大皮
Yacky, schmacky, bappy, dappy
多皮剥皮把比法比
doppy, boppy, blabby, flabby
扎皮嘎咒比皮比皮八米加
zappiga zowie, blippy bippy, blammica
你在干什么  海绵宝宝
What are you doing, SpongeBob?
章鱼哥  你回来了
Squidward, you're back
咒语生效了
The magic words worked
我原来真的有法力
I really am magic after all
我能把你变成别的东西了吗
Can I turn you into something else now?
停车
Stop
快带我走
Get me out of here
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob?
我还是很饿
I'm still hungry
能把我变成一罐蛋黄酱
Will you turn me into a jar of mayonnaise
让我自己吃自己吗
so I can eat myself?
好啊  兄弟
Sure, buddy
派大星变蛋黄酱
Patrick-ah, mayonnaise-ica
蛋黄酱